<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Tech Vagabond!</title>
    <link>https://techvagabond.org/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Tech Vagabond!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 14:57:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techvagabond.org/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patent markets: efficiency conditions for a new &#34;commodity&#34; market</title>
      <link>https://techvagabond.org/patent-markets-efficiency-conditions-for-a-new-commodity-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 14:57:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techvagabond.org/patent-markets-efficiency-conditions-for-a-new-commodity-market/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Fair valuation of patents is a difficult task. Analytics methods and methodologies exist to evaluate the financial impact of tangible assets on the performance of a business or a company, but non of them can be effectively transposed for hte valuation of intangible assets like patents. Experts suggest that the increasing volume of patents exchanges in commercial transaction signals the start of a &#34;commoditization&#34; process. A more pragmatic approach to assess a fair price would be the creation of a structured market where patents can be freely priced, traded and used as hedge instruments for commercial transactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le transfert des risques sur brevet: le marché comme solution ultime</title>
      <link>https://techvagabond.org/le-transfert-des-risques-sur-brevet-le-march%C3%A9-comme-solution-ultime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 14:57:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techvagabond.org/le-transfert-des-risques-sur-brevet-le-march%C3%A9-comme-solution-ultime/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Cet article propose une rétrospective de l&#39;évolution des marchés du brevet, depuis son statut initial d&#39;actif au service de l&#39;établissement d&#39;un monopole jusqu&#39;à devenir un marché stratégique, suivant un processus de mutation dit de commoditisation, que cet article examine en observant les modifications réalisées dans les transferts de risque au gré des mutations. L&#39;ultime étape des transformations en cours pourrait être la financiarisation ou sécurisation du brevet, cette idée est explorée dans la seconde partie de ce travail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Profits Direction in a Dataset of CAC40 Trades</title>
      <link>https://techvagabond.org/forecasting-profits-direction-in-a-dataset-of-cac40-trades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://techvagabond.org/forecasting-profits-direction-in-a-dataset-of-cac40-trades/</guid>
      <description>Our dataset consists of many possible trades generated by several different strategies and our main purpose is to identify the most useful features in order to detect the trades with positive gain and therefore the winning strategies. After having imported the data, we are going to clean in it up and to reformat them. Each record of the dataframe is a single transaction which consists of three trades. One trade to open the position and two trades to close it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
